Guide to the Records of City-As-School MC.271
New York University Archives
Records of City-As-School
1965-2019
New York University Archives
City-As-School
MC.271
5.70 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 8 manuscript boxes, and one half manuscript box
51.79 Gigabytes in 10 DVD-Rs and 7 CD-RWs.
City-As-School is a public high school in the West Village of Manhattan, New York City. The school has been distinguished by its curricular focus on experiential learning through internship, and is built on the idea that all children learn differently, some learn by seeing, some by hearing, others by doing. This collection consists of yearbooks, catalogs, anniversary and graduation ceremony programs, and other City-As-School programming materials. One 1978 softcover yearbook has drawings by Jean-Michel Basquiat on three pages. Basquiat's name is listed in the staff directory for the yearbook, and a photograph of his graffiti tag. Some of the programming materials include a scrapbook documenting City-As-School's "Our Adventure in China" (2002), Remembering Fred Koury: A Tribute and Celebration (2010-09), and City-As-Shakespeare pamphlets. This collection also includes one folder of materials created by City-As-School students and faculty during a visit to the New York University Archives. The digital media consists of graduation slideshows, school education programs regarding anti-bullying and safety, and photographs of school events.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to yearbooks and other publications is restricted, except for students and faculty of City-As-School, for five years after date of publication.
Accruals
Further accruals are expected.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The first accession was donated by City-As-School in March 2017 with an accretion in July 2017; the accession numbers associated with these gift are 2017.029 and 2017.005, respectively. An accretion of publications and ephemera were donated during a visit to the NYU Archives in May 2018; the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.014. An accretion of school records and other documents saved by former City-As-School principal and vice-principal Richard Safran was donated in July 2018; the accession number associated with this gift is 2018.023. In 2019, additional course catalogs and event ephemera was donated; the accession number associated with this gift is 2019.080
Arrangement
The order in which these materials were sent to the archives has been maintained. Five series have been identified:
Series 1: Yearbooks, 1973-2016
Series 2: Catalogs, 1990-2013
Series 3: City-As-School Anniversary Celebrations, 1993-2013
Series 4: City-As-School Press and Programming
Series 5: City-As-School Visits to NYU, 2018
Series 6: 2018 Accretion
Series 7: 2019 Accretion
Historical Note
City-As-School is a public high school in the West Village of Manhattan, New York City. Since its opening in 1972, City-As-School has been distinguished by its curricular focus on experiential learning through internship. City-As-School is built on the idea that all children learn differently: some learn by seeing, some by hearing, others by doing. The school's stated objective is to help strengthen, motivate and guide students through their high school experience.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact university-archives@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of yearbooks, catalogs, anniversary and graduation ceremony programs, and other City-As-School programming materials. One 1978 softcover yearbook has drawings by Jean-Michel Basquiat on three pages. Basquiat's name is listed in the staff directory for the yearbook, and a photograph of his graffiti tag. Some of the programming materials include a scrapbook documenting City-As-School's "Our Adventure in China" (2002), Remembering Fred Koury: A Tribute and Celebration (2010-09), and City-As-Shakespeare pamphlets. This collection also includes one folder of materials created by City-As-School students and faculty during a visit to the New York University Archives. The digital media consists of graduation slideshows, school education programs regarding anti-bullying and safety, and photographs of school events.
Yearbooks; High schools -- New York (State) -- New York; Alternative education -- New York (State); Catalogs.; Fliers (printed matter); Concert programs; Basquiat, Jean-Michel, 1960-1988
- Yearbooks, 1973-2017
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of City-As-School yearbooks dating from 1973-2016.
  - Yearbooks, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yearbooks, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yearbooks, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yearbooks, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yearbooks, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yearbooks, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yearbook, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yearbook, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yearbook, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yearbook, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Yearbook, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Yearbook, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Yearbook, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Yearbook, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Yearbook, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Yearbook, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Yearbook, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Yearbook, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Yearbook, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Yearbook, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Yearbook, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Yearbook, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Yearbooks, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Yearbook, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Yearbook, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Yearbook, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Yearbook, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Yearbook, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Yearbook, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Yearbook, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Yearbook, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Yearbook, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Yearbook, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Yearbooks, 2013-2015 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Yearbook, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Yearbook, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Catalogs, 1990-2014
  This series consists of City-As-School catalogs dating from 1990-2013. The catalogs describe the school's mission, courses, faculty and staff, and showcase select school programs.
  - Catalog, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Catalog, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Catalog, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Catalog, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Catalog, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Catalog, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Catalog, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Catalogs, 2003-2005 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Catalog, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Catalog, 2006-2007 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Catalog, 2007-2009 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Catalog, 2010-2012 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Catalog, 2012-2014 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- City-As-School Anniversary Celebrations, 1993-2013
  This series consists of City-As-School anniversary celebration programs dating from 1993-2013. There are programs and planning committee notes for the 20th, 25th, 30th, 35th, 40th anniversary ceremonies of the City-As-School project.
  - CAS 20th Anniversary, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - CAS 25th Anniversary, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - CAS 30th Anniversary, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - CAS 35th Anniversary, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - CAS 40th Anniversary, 2012-2013 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- City-As-School Press and Programming, 1974-2018
  This series consists of materials relating to various City-As-School programs including: Remembering Fred Koury: A Tribute and Celebration (2010-09), City-As-Shakespeare, and Our Adventure in China (2002).
  - CAS Propaganda, 1986-2013 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - City-As-School's Guest Book, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - A Class Magazine - City-As-School Summer Writing Institute, July 1997 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Remembering Fred Koury - A Tribute and Celebration, September 24, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - City as Shakespeare, 2018 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - City as School High - Our Adventure in China, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Program Pamphlets, 1992-2012 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 2000-2017 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Board of Education of the City of New York - Proposal for the City-As-School Project, February 16, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Debate, 2006-05-23 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - City-As-School Graduation Programs, 1974-2018 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - City-As-School Educational Programs and Celebrations' Media (Box 6, Dvd UA_MC_271-1 - UA_MC_271-10, Cd UA_MC_271-11 - UA_MC_271-17)
  - Event Flyers, 2018 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - No Earth Without Art, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Lissa's Class Poems Cycle Three, 2017 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- City-As-School Visits to NYU, 2018
  This series consists of materials created and collected during City-As-School visits to the New York University Archives beginning in 2018.
  - First Annual City-As-School Visit, 2018-05-09 (Box 6, Folder 11)